Nicole: So why is cyber
security testing so important?
Abraham: Cyber security testing
helps to identify weaknesses or
vulnerabilities before they are
found by malicious threat actors.
Nicole: By simulating the behaviour
of threat actors, cyber security
experts can help to identify any
issues with a system and how these
might potentially be exploited.
Companies often do security testing
after installing new systems, apps
and infrastructure to make sure that
every aspect of their system is secure.
By identifying these, at the time
of installation, weaknesses or
vulnerabilities can be assessed and
organisations can prioritise and
handle any risks more effectively.
Abraham: Different types of testing
can show up different weaknesses.
For example, social engineering testing
can highlight issues with procedures
and identify how susceptible staff
might be to social engineering attacks.
This can then be used can be used to
develop training to raise staff awareness.
Nicole: Pen testing can help personnel
learn how to handle a malicious
attack if it happens for real.
Red teaming or ethical hacking can be used
to systematically identify an attack path
looking for all the unnoticeable gaps such
as backdoors, open windows, and other ways
of breaching an organisation’s system.
Abraham: Cyber security testing can
be costly, but it can save more money
in the long term as it can protect
against expensive cyber-attacks that
could impact an organisation in the
way it functions and its reputation.
Nicole: Think of the costs involved in
an expensive ransomware attack, losing
data to competitors, replacing software
and hardware or even data, and any fines
that go along with it for breaching GDPR.
Abraham: Imagine how costly it could
be for an organisation to suffer
significant downtime especially if
they have to close down the system
and go offline to fix the problem.
Nicole: Some standards require
organisations to perform regular
penetration or other types of
security testing to meet industry
standards and regulations.
Such as ISO 27001 the standard
for information security and GDPR
where organisations that process
Personal information and data,
have to make sure that they have
appropriate security measures in
place to identify vulnerabilities.
The PCI DSS Payment card industry data
security standard requires vulnerability
scanning as part of its standard.
Abraham: Security testing and evaluating
testing is a proactive approach that
helps to identify the potential security
risks and help to show how to fix issues.
It helps to reduce threats and risks
in systems to minimize the chance of
loss resulting from a cybersecurity
breach and taking data protection
seriously, by regular testing, helps
organisations to cement a relationship
of trust with their customers.